Finding aid to the Administrative Offices records CA.MS.01005
Smith College Archives
Administrative Offices records
1875-2001
Smith College Archives
Smith College.
CA.MS.01005
57.667 linear feet (136 containers)
Administrative Offices records include pamphlets, office files, exams, reports, meeting minutes.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials in the Smith College Archives are open for use, with the following exceptions: "Office Files," files of records created for the use of the administrative unit that created them, are closed to research for a period of 10 years following their creation. Faculty tenure and promotion files, as well as inactive faculty files are closed permanently. Board of Trustees' records are closed permanently. In all cases, the College Archives will continue to provide public access to materials that were intended to be public at the time of their creation (press releases, publications, etc.)
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Unknown source.
Other Finding Aids
Many of the accessions in the collection have container lists that are available upon request by contacting specialcollections@smith.edu
Scope and Contents
Administrative Offices records include pamphlets, office files, exams, reports, meeting minutes. The collection is arranged alphabetically by name of office.
Biographical / Historical
The term "Administrative Offices" is not a singular entity but rather refers to a group of offices that oversee the daily function of administration within Smith College.
Conditions Governing Access
Until we move into New Neilson in early 2021, collections are stored in multiple locations and may take up to 48 hours to retrieve. Researchers are strongly encouraged to contact Special Collections (specialcollections@smith.edu) at least a week in advance of any planned visits so that boxes may be retrieved for them in a timely manner.
Smith College -- Administration; Smith College -- Administration
- Academic Computing Center, Academic Assistance (CAIS), Academic Development Center, Affirmative Action (Box 530)
- Admissions Office
  - Accredited Schools - Applications: Freshmen (Box 531)
  - Applications: Freshman - Special Talents (Box 531.1)
  - Applications: Transfer Students - Visiting students (Box 531.2)
  - General: Athletics - College Entrance Exams (Box 531.3)
  - General: College Recruitment - Z (Box 531.4)
  - Picture Books (Box 531.5)
  - Enrollment Studies, 1991-2001 (Box 532.1)
  - Enrollment Studies, 1991-2001 (Box 532.2)
  - Entrance Deposit Receipts, 1965-1967 (Box 533)
  - Advanced Standing, 1933-1938 (Box 534)
  - Minutes, 1914-1947 (Box 535)
  - Applicant Statistics and College Board scores, 1957-1958 (Box 536)
  - Applicant Statistics and College Board Scores, 1959-1960 (Box 537)
  - Applicant Statistics and College Board Scores, 1961-1962 (Box 538)
  - Applicant Statistics and College Board Scores, 1963-1965 (Box 539)
- Dean of the College
  - A-Q: Academic Dean, Business Dean, Office of Class Deans (Box 540)
  - R-Z: Dean of Enrollment, Dean of Faculty (Box 541)
  - Time Survey, 1934 (Box 542)
  - Student Affairs Office, Roommate Contract (Box 542.1)
  - Student Affairs Office, Warden, Student Organization Guides (Box 543)
  - Student Affairs: Housing - Residential Life Manuals, House President Manuals, House Council List, House Community Program, 1993-1999 (Box 543.1)
  - Dean of Social Affairs, Head of House Manuals (Box 543.2)
  - Dean of Social Affairs, Head of house Meeting Notes, 1927-1963 (Box 544)
  - Bridge Program, Minority Affairs Office, Orientation (Box 544.1)
  - House Lists, 1933-1947 (Box 544.2)
  - House Lists, 1947-1958 (Box 544.3)
  - House Lists, 1958-1968 (Box 544.4)
  - House Lists, 1968-1980 (Box 544.5)
- Development Office
  - Development Program: General A-Pub (F) (Box 545)
  - General Publications G-Z (Box 545.1)
  - Campaigns, Fundraising, 1970-1999 (Box 547)
  - Grants A-Hew (OE-IV) (Box 547.1)
  - Grants Hew (OE-V) (Box 547.2)
  - Grants Hew (P-Z) - National (Box 547.3)
  - Grants, National Science Foundation, 1966 (Box 547.4)
  - Grants, National Science Foundation, 1967 (Box 547.5)
  - Grants, National Science Foundation (Box 547.6)
  - Capital Campaigns, 1959-1962 (Box 546)
  - Campaigns, Fundraising, 1965-1979 (Box 546.1)
- Dining Services (Box 547.7)
  - Smith Dining 2016 Strategic Planning website, Captured 2018 July 12; 1 website
    Scope and Contents
    The goal of the Smith College Dining Services Strategic Planning initiative was "to analyze the current program with an eye toward understanding current patterns of use, enhancing sustainability performance, emphasizing health and wellness, and improving operational efficiencies." The website documenting this plan was captured in 2018.
- D - Financial Aid Applications (Box 547.8)
- Fellowship Program
  - Smith College Fellowships Program website, First captured July 2019; 1 website (1 archived website)
    The Smith College Fellowships Program advises Smith students and recent alumnae who wish to apply for competitive national and international fellowships. This archived website (https://sophia.smith.edu/fellowships-information/) was first captured in 2019.
  - Five-minute Fulbright Field Notes, First captured July 2019; 1 website (1 archived website)
    Smith College Fulbright alumnae write about their journeys around the world in a blog entitled "Five-minute Fulbright Field Notes" (https://fellowsmithie.wordpress.com/). The archived website was first captured in 2019.
- Financial Aid (Box 547.8a)
- Health - IS (Box 547.9)
  - Health services websites
    - Wellness at Smith blog, 2012-2014; website captured; 1 website
      The Wellness at Smith blog (https://wellnessatsmith.wordpress.com/) was active 2012-2014 and included news, resources, and events sponsored by Health and Wellness services for students, and educational posts for students on various topics including stress, sexuality, relationships, drug and alcohol abuse, and body image. The archived blog was captured in 2019.
- Human Resources
  - Human Resources (Box 549)
  - Handbooks for Administrative and Clerical Staff (Box 549.1)
  - General: Clerical Staff Handbook, June, 1984 (Box 549.2)
  - Five Staff Handbooks, 1983-1999 (Box 549.3)
  - Institutional Affairs, Institutional Diversity, International Students Office (Box 550)
  - Smith employment opportunities website, first captured 2015; 1 website
    The archived website of the Smith College employment opportunities website (https://smithcollege.hiretouch.com/) was first captured in 2015. Subsequent captures are scheduled periodically. The site is managed by the Office of Human resources and lists current staff and faculty positions available at Smith.
    Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
    The searchable database is not available in the archived version of this site, but job listings can be viewed in the "Browse Jobs" view.
    Related Materials
    The archived website of the Smith College Department of Human Resources is captured as part of the larger Smith College archived website.
- Information Technology Services
  - Computer Store website, First captured 2019; 1 website (1 archived website)
- Ombudsperson, Physical Plant (Box 550.1)
- Office of the President (Box 550.2)
- College Relations
  - News Releases: Gifts, 1940-1975 (Box 551.1)
  - General: Releases, Notes, Clippings, Brochures, 1875-1979 (Box 551.2)
  - General: Releases, Notes, Clippings, Brochures, Purchasing Department History, 1980-2000 (Box 551.3)
- Office of the Registrar
  - Curriculum, Course of Study, Course of Study Changes, Interim, Schedules, Science (Box 553)
  - Curriculum: Interim Questionnaire, 1962 (Box 554)
  - Smith College online Course Catalog, 2003-2019; first captured 2016 Aug 24; 1 website
    The Smith College online course catalog (https://catalog.smith.edu/) was first captured in 2016. Subsequent captures are scheduled annually. Whle the live database is not available in the archived version of this website, there are PDF versions of the catalogs available going back to 2003-04.
    Digitized versions of the course catalogs (1872-2011) are also available in the Internet Archive.
  - Curriculum: Interim Course Catalogs (Box 555)
  - Examinations
    - 40b Honor Senior Exams, 1951-1966 (Box 555.1)
    - Exams, 1950-1951, 1956-1957, 1958 (Box 556)
    - Field, 1967-1970 (Box 557)
    - German (Box 558)
    - Classics (Box 559)
    - Economics (Box 559.1)
    - Chinese (Box 559.2)
    - Education and Child Study (Box 559.3)
    - Biological Sciences (Box 560)
    - Geology (Box 561)
    - Botany, Chemistry, Microbiology (Box 562)
    - Greek (Box 563)
    - French - Box 1: French 3-112 (and misc. exams) (Box 563.1)
    - French - Box 2: French 113-310 (Box 564)
    - French - Box 3: French 311-418 (Box 564.1)
    - Art (Box 565)
    - Afro-American Studies, American Studies, Ancient Studies, Arabic, Astronomy, Bacteriology, Biochemistry (Box 566)
    - Latin (Box 566.1)
    - Government (Box 567)
    - Hispanic Studies (Spanish and Portuguese) (Box 568)
    - History 1-226 (Box 569)
    - History 230-373 (Box 569.1)
    - History and Social Sciences and Miscellaneous History Exams (Box 570)
    - Italian (Box 571)
    - General Literature, Geometry, Hygiene, Latin American Studies, Music, Physical Science (Box 572)
    - Mathematics (Box 573)
    - Philosophy (Box 574)
    - Physics (Box 575)
    - Psychology (Box 575.1)
    - Religion (Box 576)
    - Russian (Box 576.1)
    - Sociology (Box 577)
    - Speech and Theater (Box 577.1)
    - Zoology (Box 578)
    - Dance, Honors Exams 23-28, Norwegian, Public Policy, Social Science, Time Schedules for Exams and Blue Books (Box 578.1)
- Social Regulations A-C (Box 579)
- Social Regulations D-Z (Box 580)
- Special Programs
  - Ada Comstock Scholars Program (Box 582)
  - I.S. 201 Program: Senior Administrative Management Seminar (Box 583)
- Students' Aid Society (Box 583.1)
- Summer Programs
  - Community College Connections program records, 1996-2003; 2018-A-0074; Community College Connections program; .5 linear feet (1 letter document box) (Box 583.4)
    Conditions Governing Access
    Materials in the Smith College Archives are open for use, with the following exceptions: "Office Files," files of records created for the use of the administrative unit that created them, are closed to research for a period of 10 years following their creation.
    Biographical / Historical
    Smith College's Community College Connections (CCC) program will gave women from five community colleges across the country the chance to focus exclusively on learning. CCC was designed to provide students at community colleges with the residential college experience, to help them then decide whether they were interested in going on to a four-year college. The program also sought to identify and serve students who are the first in their families to go to college, most of whom had never considered the possibility of attending a four-year college.
    Office files, photographs, evaluations, annual reports
    Community College Connections program
  - Current Students/Future Scientists and Engineers (Box 583.3)
  - SP: Brochures, photographs and specific program files (Box 583.2)
- Treasurer's Office
  - A - I (Box 584)
  - J - Z (Box 584.1)
  - Scholarships, Student Aid Office, Coop Housing (Box 585)
  - Tre - Z (Box 586)
  - Finance Committee
    - FC, 1946-1950 (Box 587)
    - FC, 1950-1953 (Box 588)
    - FC, 1953-1956 (Box 589)
    - FC, 1956-1959 (Box 590)
    - FC, 1959-1962 (Box 591)
  - Early Records: Cash Accounts, Canceled Checks (Box 592)
  - Finance Committee, 1955-1979 (Box 593)
  - Financial Reports, 1886, 1899-1914 (Box 594)
  - Finance Committee's Financial Reports
    - FCFR, 1923-1949 (Box 595)
    - FCFR, 1950-1962 (Box 596)
    - FCFR, 1963-1975 (Box 597)
    - FCFR, 1976-1982 (Box 598)
    - FCFR, 1982-1995 (Box 598.1)
  - Financial Reports - Audits, 1930-1936 (Box 599)
  - Funds
    - History of Funds, 1882/1883 to 1931/1932 (Box 600)
    - Stand By Smith, $2,000,000 and $4,000,000, 1919-1920 (Box 601)
    - Stand By Smith, $4,000,000, 1919-1920 (Box 601.1)
    - Oversize and Memorabilia (Box 601.2)
    - Funds, 1950, $7,000,000
      - A - H (Box 602)
      - I - Z (Box 603)
      - Alumnae Association Assembly Show, Alumnae Fund, Campaign Report Books I-III (Box 604)
      - Campaign Report Books IV, Campaign Workers (Box 605)
    - Alumnae Fund
      - AF, 1928-1955 (Box 606)
      - AF, 1955-1980 (Box 607)
      - AF, 1980-1997 (Box 607.1)
      - AF - Sophia Smith Associates (Box 608)
  - Financial Report of Student Organizations
    - FROSO, 1947-1957 (Box 610)
    - FROSO, 1957-1966 (Box 611)
- Vocational Office/Career Development Office
  - A - Praxis (Box 612)
  - Pub - Z (Box 612.1)
  - Employment Notices, Questionnaires - Summer Work, 1964-1972 (Box 613)
  - College Internship Program (Box 614)
  - The Smith College Job Guide (Box 614.1)